singletrackworld.com 2018-12-15

# Privacy Policy - Singletrack Magazine

### **Privacy & Cookies Policy**

This Privacy & Cookies Policy explains the practices employed by Gofar Enterprises Ltd in collecting and using your information and the ways in which you can influence these. This Privacy & Cookies Policy relates to websites operated from time to time by Gofar Enterprises Ltd.

Gofar Enterprises Ltd will collect various types of information about you through your use of our websites to process your requests and orders, to provide a more personalised web-surfing and shopping experience and to help us improve the services we offer. In doing this we may also collect information about you through the use of cookies and similar technologies. Gofar Enterprises Ltd will be the Data Controller of any personal data we collect about you.

### **What information do we collect about you?**

Through Gofar Enterprises Ltd websites you can, amongst other things, order products and services, enter competitions, subscribe to our publications, vote in polls, play games, complete surveys and place postings on forums.

In order to process your requests and orders and other activities, it may be necessary to collect personal information about you. This includes, but is not limited to: your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, credit/debit card information. You may also be asked to provide additional (non-mandatory) pieces of information for our research purposes or choose to provide information by making a posting on a forum.

In addition, we collect technical information about your device such as your unique device ID as well as information about your visits to and your activity on our websites including the content (and any advertisements) that you view and interact with, the address of the website from which you arrived and other clickstream behaviour (such as the pages you view, the links you click or which items you have added to your shopping basket, the length of your internet session, your IP address and the approximate location at the time of browsing). Some of this information is collected using cookies or similar technologies. To learn more about these technologies and your choices, go to the section on **‘Cookies and other technologies’** below.

Some of our websites offer services that require you to set up an account prior to receiving such services. To create a secure account you may use your email address and a password or, if the website offers a Facebook single-sign-on service, you will be able to register for and log-in to your Gofar Enterprises Ltd website account using your Facebook account.

If you choose to use a Facebook single-sign-on service, you are granting permission to Facebook to share certain profile information with us. This will include your name, profile picture and list of friends and any other information notified to you by Facebook prior to you completing the single-sign-on authorisation process.

### **How will we use the information about you?**

We will use the information you provide to us to process your orders and requests. We may also use this information to communicate with you directly, for example to notify you in the event you have won a competition or to contact you in relation to an account you hold with us.

We will use the information we automatically collect about you to analyse web usage and compile aggregate statistics about our users. We may share this aggregated and de-identified data with third parties.

### **Personalisation and Advertising**

We will use your information to provide you with personalised content, services and communications as well as targeted advertising on our websites, websites operated by our group companies and selected partner websites (for example, you might see an advertisement on a partner site such as Facebook for a product that you have recently viewed on our websites). We may do this by matching, combining or linking the different sources of information we hold about you (e.g. linking your contact or subscriber information with your activity across our websites or by linking your activity on our websites across all your devices using your email or social media log-in details) or by creating segments based on various factors such as your age and gender, your device details or your inferred interests. 

We may share some of your information with advertisers, ad servers and ad networks to deliver targeted advertising both on our websites and on selected partner websites but this will not include any information which directly identifies you. However, by interacting with or viewing an advert, you should be aware that the third party may make the assumption that you meet the targeting criteria used to display the advert.

These activities may involve the use of cookies and other similar technologies.  To learn more or to see how you can opt out of targeted advertising, please see the section on **‘Cookies and other technologies’** below.

### **Marketing**

Where we have the appropriate permissions, we will use your information to market and advertise products and services from Gofar Enterprises Ltd, and occasionally third party products and services that may be of interest to you including third party offers, advertisements, competitions or commercial communications by telephone (mobile and landline when available), post, electronic messaging (including SMS and MMS), email, online or via applications. 

You can always tell us that you wish to stop receiving direct marketing communications from us. But remember, if you do not want us to get in touch, you may miss out on valuable and exciting offers. If you would prefer not to receive direct marketing communications, simply let us know at any time by writing to the Customer Services Manager at Gofar Enterprises Ltd, Gofar Enterprises Ltd, Lockside Mill, Dale Street, Todmorden OL14 5PX, UK or subs@singletrackworld.com with the subject line “Privacy”, or by following the opt out instructions in the relevant communication. Please note that this will not stop you from receiving service messages from us.

You can also make choices about the use of cookies and targeted advertising. For more information about this, please refer to our section on **‘Cookies and other technologies’** below.

### **What will we disclose to third parties?**

We may pass your personal information to third parties to enable them to process a request, order or service; to supply you with a prize in the event you win a competition; or in order to obtain professional advice. Any third parties employed by us to process your data on our behalf are subject to contractual obligations to protect the security of your data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy & Cookies Policy.

We may provide aggregate information to advertisers and our business partners, including information relating to sales and web-usage, to enable us to sell advertising and monitor the efficacy of our business partnerships. We may also pass such statistical information onto reputable third parties for onward sale.

It is possible that Gofar Enterprises Ltd could merge or be acquired by another business. If this happens we may share the information that relates to you. You will be sent notice of such an event. Gofar Enterprises Ltd reserves the right to disclose personal information in order to comply with the law, applicable regulations and government requests. We also reserve the right to use such information in order to protect our operating systems and integrity as well as other users.

### **How do we protect your information?**

Once we have received your data we will ensure that it is treated with the utmost respect and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 as well as the latest GDPR legislation. Your data will be stored on our secure servers. We follow strict security procedures in order that the data we collect is stored and disclosed appropriately and securely. Unfortunately the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although Gofar Enterprises Ltd will do its best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk.

### **Other Websites**

Please note that clicking on links and advertisements on our websites may result in your transferral to another website, where data privacy practices may vary to that of Gofar Enterprises Ltd. If transferred to another site you should consult their privacy policy as we are not responsible for, and have no control over, information that is submitted to or collected by these third parties.

### **Changes to our Privacy & Cookies policy**

Gofar Enterprises Ltd keeps this Privacy & Cookies policy under review and may update it at any time. Any updates will be made on this page so that you can always find out what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we will disclose it.

### **How to contact us**

If you have any queries relating to this Privacy & Cookies Policy please contact us by writing to the Customer Services Manager at Gofar Enterprises Ltd, Lockside Mill, Dale Street, Todmorden OL14 5PX, UK or dataprotection@singletrackworld.com with the subject line “Privacy”.

### **Cookies and other technologies**

We use, and allow certain other companies to use, cookies, web beacons and other similar technologies on our websites, applications and communications. We do this to understand your use of our services, improve your user experience and enable personalised features and content; optimise our advertising and marketing and to enable third party advertising companies to assist us in serving you advertisements specific to your interests across the internet. Please see **‘How to manage or refuse cookies and similar technologies’** for more information.

You can find more detailed information about these technologies at:

### **What are ‘cookies’?**

A cookie is a small text file that we, and in certain circumstances third parties, place on your browser (for example, Internet Explorer or Safari) when you visit our websites or open some of our emails. Cookies are useful because, amongst other things, they allow us to recognise you each time you re-visit one of our websites. The entity that places cookies on your browser can then read the information on the cookie that it set.

Cookies are typically classified as either “session cookies” which do not stay on your device after you close your browser or “persistent cookies” which will usually remain on your device until you delete them or they expire.

### **How we and third parties use cookies**

We use cookies that are essential in order to enable you to move around our websites and use their features, such as accessing secure areas of the websites. Without these cookies, services that you have asked for like shopping baskets cannot be provided.

Some cookies, however, whilst useful, are not essential, and we require your consent before we can use these cookies. By continuing to browse on our Gofar Enterprises Ltd websites you agree to the use of these non-essential cookies unless you specifically set your browser to reject them. Please see **‘How to manage or refuse cookies and similar technologies’** below for further details on your choices.

Different cookies are used to perform different functions which we explain below. A visit to any Gofar Enterprises Ltd. website may generate the following types of cookie:

### **Site performance cookies**

**We use cookies to remember your selections on our websites:** These cookies allow us to remember choices you make on our websites and provide enhanced, more personalised features. These cookies can also be used to remember changes you have made to text size, fonts and other parts of web pages that you can customise. They may also be used to provide services you have asked for such as watching a video or commenting on a blog. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

### **Analytics cookies**

**We use cookies for performance and analytics purposes:** We use our own cookies and/or third-party cookies and other identifiers (such as web beacons) to see how you use our websites and services in order to enhance their performance and develop them according to the preferences of our customers and visitors. For example, cookies and web beacons may be used to: test different designs and to ensure that we maintain a consistent look and feel across our websites; recognise repeat visitors, track and provide trend analysis on how our users interact with our websites and communications; track errors and measure the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns.

The information collected from these types of cookies may be used in conjunction with other information we or our third party partners hold in order to record specific browsing information (for example, regarding the way visitors arrive at our websites, pages viewed, options selected, information entered and the path taken through our websites but is generally not used to identify you individually). The data collected will generally be aggregated to provide trends and usage patterns for business analysis, site/platform improvement and performance metrics and to inform our advertising and marketing strategies. Our cookies, or the resulting analysis, may also be shared with our business partners. 

**Advertising cookies**

**We use cookies to personalise your experience and for targeted advertising purposes:** We use cookies (and allow data management platform providers to use cookies on our behalf) to collect information about your browsing habits across our websites in order to provide personalised content, services and communications as well as targeted advertising on our websites. If you use more than one device or computer on a regular basis, we may link cookies together so you will still receive a personalised online experience. We can also personalise the information you see based on what we already know about you, so that you spend less time looking for things. With the use of cookies, each visitor to our site can have a web experience which is unique to them.

Cookies may also be linked with other information we hold or infer about you for these purposes. For example, if you are a registered user or provide us with your name, email address, social media log-in details or other contact information (e.g. by entering a competition or signing up to our newsletter) or interact with our email communications (e.g. by clicking on links within the emails), this information may be linked with your browsing activity across all your devices to tailor content, services, advertising and offers for you.

You can opt out of receiving interest based advertising on our websites by blocking these cookies as described below in the section on **‘How to manage or refuse cookies and similar technologies’**.

### **Third party advertising cookies**

We also permit advertisers, ad network providers and ad serving companies to place cookies on our websites to allow them to show you advertisements both on and off our websites that are more relevant and useful to you. However, we do not share any information with these third parties that will directly identify you, although these third parties may assume that users who interact with or click on a personalised advertisements or content are part of the group that the advertisement or content is directed towards. The third parties that generate these cookies have their own privacy policies and we have no access to read or write these cookies.

### **Social media cookies**

Cookies may also be used when you share information using a social media sharing button on the websites. The social network will record that you have done this. This information may be linked to targeting/advertising activities. The types of cookies used by these third parties and how they use the information generated by them will be governed by those companies’ privacy policies. For information on how to opt out of targeting advertising, please go to **‘How to manage or refuse cookies and similar technologies’** below.

### **How we and third parties use web beacons**

We may use and permit selected third parties to use web beacons (usually in combination with cookies) to compile aggregate information about your website usage and your interaction with email and other communications to measure performance and to provide content and advertisements that are more relevant to you. A web beacon (also called a web bug, clear GIF or pixel tag) can be embedded in online content, videos and emails, and allows a server to read certain types of information from your device, to know when you have viewed the beacon and the IP address of your device. The type of information collected includes, but is not limited to, information relating to advertising responses, page views, promotion views and purchases made. We will include web beacons in some of our promotional email messages and newsletters to determine whether the messages have been opened or acted upon and whether our mailing tools are working correctly. The web beacons may be used to recognise cookies generated by third parties and inform us and/or third parties of which advertisement or link brought you to our website, allowing us to monitor the efficacy of our business relationships with third parties.

### **How to manage or refuse cookies and similar technologies**

### **Cookies**

If you do not want your browser to accept cookies and use them in the ways described above it is possible to change your browser settings. It is also possible to delete existing cookies from your browser. However, blocking all cookies will affect your web experience and may result in some parts of Gofar Enterprises Ltd websites not functioning properly. Some cookies are designed to help save you time, for example, by remembering your contact details when you are making an order for the second time so that you will not have to complete the contact section again unless your details have changed.

The procedure for modifying your privacy preferences is different for each internet browser and the following links may be helpful:

For general information about cookies and their use, please visit:

Alternatively, you can turn off third party cookies relating to interest based advertising by visiting[ www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). However, this will not opt you out of receiving adverts altogether – it simply means that the adverts will not be targeted to you. Please note that there are many more networks listed on this site than we use on our websites.

### **Web beacons**

As web beacons are the same as any other content request included in the recipe for a web page, you cannot opt out or refuse them. However, you may be able to disable web beacons in email messages by not downloading images contained in messages you receive (this feature varies depending on the email software used on your personal computer). However, doing this may not always disable a web beacon or other tracking technologies in the email message due to specific email software capabilities. For more information about this, please refer to the information provided by your email software or service provider. Web beacons may also be rendered ineffective in some circumstances by opting out of cookies or amending your cookie settings in your browser. Further details on web beacons, and how to manage them, can be found here:

If you have any other queries about our use of cookies, you can contact us at the address above.

**Our Third Party Services and why we use them.**

The following is a detailed list of the third party services that we may use on our website in order to track our website performance (Analytics), and monetise it through advertising. We may not use them all at any one time. The transmission of some of your personal data, such as IP address and the subsequent transmission of a cookie to your device is a necessary part of their function. It may be possible to opt out of sharing your data with some of these service providers. In some cases this is via a consent popup window that contains instructions and options for opting out. Some of these services are essential parts of our website and allow it and our business to operate effectively. These services are essential parts of our website and you cannot opt out of using them. If you would rather your data was not shared with these essential services then, unless these services have a mechanism to allow you to opt out your only option is to stop using our website.

**Google Analytics:**

Our legitimate reason for this code: To enable us to measure the performance of all parts of the website and to give us overall website performance information that helps us to improve users experiences. We also share the anonymised data with third parties such as advertisers who need to know the performance of the websites they invest marketing spend with. No user identifiable information is included in any data shared with third parties although your username and IP address is passed to Google in order to compile accurate statistics on web usage.

Opt out link – Info here [https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/user-opt-out](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/user-opt-out)

**Google Adsense:**

Legitimate reason for this code: Google Adsense allows us to monetise our website and content by delivering advertisements from third party advertisers on our website.

**Skimlinks**

Skimlinks allows us to monetise our website in a way that is virtually invisible and unobtrusive to the users experience on our website. It helps us to balance more traditional revenue streams such as display advertising in favour of the user experience. We also use it to provide analysis of sales trends through reports that indicate the sales values for individual retailers but at no point do we see identifiable user data.

Users get opt out option automatically after clicking a skimlinks enable link on the site unless they have previously given Skimlink consent on other websites. Users can check their opt in/out status and change it here [http://optout.skimlinks.com/](http://optout.skimlinks.com/)

**Automatad**

Third party Ad delivery network.

Automatad allows us to monetise our website and content by delivering advertisements from third party advertisers on our website. It does this by refreshing an existing ad position on the site after a period of around 20 seconds. This is a valuable way of generating ad revenue for us without increasing the number of ad positions on the page.

You can read their privacy policy here – https://www.automatad.com/privacy-policy.php

**Next Millenium**

Ad delivery network 

Millenium inserts ads into the content of the page automatically and also inserts ads in the empty spaces at the sides of our website on desktops. It uses cookies to monitor users behaviour in order to only insert ads appropriately that are not overly frequent. This is why you may see ads in one position on one page but not on subsequent pages you visit.

**AOL One Advertising:**

We use services from AOL One Advertising to deliver our advertisers ad campaigns on our website. Cookies are used in order to deliver advertisements in a trackable and controlled way. For example cookies are used in order to limit the display of ads to users. Typically, advertisers request their ad is only shown to a user a certain number of times per day. Cookies are necessary to ensure that campaigns are delivered to the advertisers specification. These cookies also allow us to create a user friendly advertising experience and are vital to helping us monetise our website to ensure we can continue to provide a free at point of use service for all our users.

AOL One Advertising also delivers advertising campaigns from third party, carefully selected advertisers. This is known as the AOL Marketplace and we can vet the advertisers who can access this marketplace. This is a vital revenue stream that allows us to monetise our website and provide a free at point of delivery service to all our users.

**Advanced Ads**

WordPress Ad delivery software plugin

This is a software tool we use to provide further fine control of how our ads are delivered on our website. It is the primary tool used to ensure that registered users see fewer ads than none registered users. It is also the mechanism that allows us to deactivate advertising for all our website paying subscribers. This cookie stores information such as how many times a user has seen ads within a given time period in order to better control the users ad experience. It is a vital part of the functionality of our website. No personally identifiable information is transmitted to any third parties.

**Facebook Pixel:**

We use Facebook Pixel code in order to track website use by Facebook visitors. The primary use of this code is to provide us with performance information on content and better guide our content creation policies. We also use it to create anonymised audience segments of Facebook users that we can then use to create targeted ad campaigns highlighting our content, goods and services on the Facebook platform.

**SOVRN** – Ad delivery network

SOVRN is a programmatic ad provider that can use personal information such as your IP address to serve you targeted advertising. We work closely with SOVRN to ensure that all data processing is compliant with the new GDPR standards.

You can see SOVRN’s privacy policy here [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

**CRITEO**

Criteo is a retargeting advertising delivery network. This means that it uses your previous browsing history to better serve you relevant advertising. It also serves non-tracking advertising based on the general audience demographic of our website. We have ensured that Criteo is fully compliant with the new GDPR standards. You can read more about how Criteo has prepared for GDPR compliance here.

**Carambola**

Carambola deliver target advertising to our website via an interactive ad unit that displays on both desktop and mobile devices. IP address information and other browsing activity can be passed to this advertising vendor who is fully GDPR compliant.

Carambola’s Privacy policy can be viewed here [http://www.carambola.com/privacyPolicy/index.html](http://www.carambola.com/privacyPolicy/index.html)

**SORTABLE** – Ad delivery network via header bidding

Sortable is currently our biggest ad delivery provider. They take up almost 100% of our inventory that is left over after our principal and high priority advertising campaigns have displayed. They carry a heavy burden in ensuring they deliver high quality advertising campaigns to our our users and they have put a lot of effort into ensuring they are fully GDPR compliant. They are a vital part of the monetisation streams that keep Singletrack running.

Sortable’s Privacy Policy and statement of GDPR compliance is here 

All of the above advertising providers and tools have been very carefully selected by us at Singletrack to ensure a high degree of quality and balance between vital revenue flow and user experience. We, hope that you will trust our selection of these third party advertising providers and delivery tools and agree to consent to their use within your browser. 

**Links to other websites**

Contributions from other users, in the form of links within posts in the forums and in comments may involve the hotlinking or embedding of images and content from other websites. It is important to note that where such content is displayed in a users browser this will necessarily include the transmission of personal data in the form of your IP address to the server that hosts that content. This will most likely simply involve your IP address being included in the server log of that website. Since we have no direct control over the content posted by other forum users we cannot be held responsible for the transmission of your personal data in these cases. In the vast majority of situations this is perfectly normal and simply the way the internet works, but it’s important to be aware that your IP address could be transmitted to a third party website in this way.

### Your personal data stored in our databases and servers

In order to be able to post comments or create and interact with posts and topics on our forums you must first register an account. This account will store your email address, your username and, if you post to our website, your IP address at the time of posting.

In addition to this data registered users have the option to include further information in their account profile: for example Date of birth, answers to security questions used in the management of your account and other optional information. Some of this information is set to private by default and no other users or site visitors can access it. Some of this data can be set to public view by the user.

In the instance where a user has requested the deletion of their personal data and the subsequent deletion of their registered account, and where such a request has been granted by Gofar Enterprises ltd, all of this data will be permanently deleted from our servers. However, there is an exception to this rule which is detailed here.

Where a user has not posted to our website in either our forums or in comments attached to stories then we will delete all data, including passwords and the username of the user. However, where a user has posted a comment on our website or posted in our forums then the username of that user will be permanently attributed to that post, even if subsequently the user requests that their account be deleted.

In other words, while we acknowledge that your username is your personal data, where you have posted publicly on our website you are agreeing that your username will be permanently displayed to the public along with the content of your posts. This is stipulated in our website terms and conditions where you agree to assign to Gofar Enterprises Ltd a universal, non-exclusive right to keep, publish and distribute your publicly posted comments including your author attribution, which in this case is your username.

In the event that you have posted to our website all other personal data belonging to you will be deleted if such a request is granted by us. Your username will be retained in our records in order to protect the integrity and usability of our forums and comments. Retaining your username in such instances where you have used your account to publish to our website also allows us to protect your identity in the future by preventing a future user from registering an account and using your username to publish on our website. In such instances your identity could be compromised and other users could be confused as to the integrity of the existing posts on our forum.

To further ensure the security of our website as well as yourself and to reduce instances of abuse from other users, we will also retain the IP addresses used at the time your posts were published to our website. We use IP addresses to, among other things, protect our website from DOS and DDOS attacks as well as to block users who break the rules of our forums. It is a vital function of our security and moderation policies that we retain IP addresses of users who post publicly to our website in order to prevent abuse by other forum users.

### Data backups

We take daily backups of our website data, which includes backups of users personal data. These backups are securely stored for archival purposes in compliance with GDPR.

**Deletion of inactive accounts**

Our policy is to consider a registered account as inactive if the user has not logged in to their account for a period of 3 years. After this time the users’ account will be scheduled for deletion from our servers.

**Deletion of inactive accounts (Subscribers)**

In line with our accounting policy lapsed accounts of paying subscribers will be considered as inactive after a period of 6 years. After this time the users account and financial data will be scheduled for deletion from our servers.
